<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<news>
  <article date="14/03/2018" title="STUDENTS GIVE UP TECHNOLOGY FOR A WEEK">
    <title>STUDENTS GIVE UP TECHNOLOGY FOR A WEEK</title>
    <headerImage>http://thestudioliverpool.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/02/Studio-Disconnect_6.jpg</headerImage>
    <content>
      For a school that is built upon technology and digital media, you may find it ironic that we asked 200 of our students to give up technology for a week.

      We decided to participate in the “Reconnect Project”, a project which encourages youths to step away from their passive, digitally focused lives and become young creators.

      As well as confiscating the student’s mobile phones, we challenged them to stay away from their games consoles, laptops, tablets and social media.

      It wasn’t just the students who participated, teachers were also challenged to deliver lessons using offline materials only.

      One of the students, Abbey Laird, said “I think I’ll be more social with my family,” before she started the experiment. “Usually when I’m home I just go upstairs, put my headphones in and ignore what’s going on.”

      Understandably, some of the pupils expressed concerns about having to give up technology. “We’re used to it being there for us so it’s going to be hard. Everywhere you look in this school there’s technology – it feels more like a workplace,” said Kajetan Dwidowicz.

      Students found the challenge difficult at first, however agreed that as the week progressed it gradually got easier. “The first day was horrible. No social media, nothing to do. But it got easier as the week went on.”

      Amy Doyle, one of the students undertaking the task, recognised the positive effect the challenge was having on her. “I’ve started speaking to my mum more, reading more and going to sleep instead of staying up all hours.”
    </content>
  </article>
  <article date="16/05/2018" title="STUDENT GAME JAM CELEBRATION">
    <title>STUDENT GAME JAM CELEBRATION</title>
    <headerImage>http://thestudioliverpool.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/IMG_2828.jpg</headerImage>
    <content>
      At the end of last term students from The Studio hosted a mid-year exhibition to showcase their work and ongoing projects.

      The Game Jam invited all students to gather their work and create promotional materials to exhibit their game or project at a celebration of creativity. Partners and industry mentors attended the exhibition and provided constructive feedback and ideas for progression.

      The mid-year exhibition helps to prepare students for the end of year showcase which is a final celebration attended by parents, staff and industry mentors.
    </content>
  </article>
  <article date="" title="">
    <title>NDUSTRIAL CADET PROGRAMME PROVIDES INSIGHT INTO ENGINEERING</title>
    <headerImage>http://thestudioliverpool.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/IMG_3087.jpg</headerImage>
    <content>
      Students from Years 10, 11, 12 and 13 at The Studio in Liverpool attended a series of workshops earlier this month as part of an Industrial Cadet Programme.

      The Studio has been working with the NAC Group F1 in Schools Programme Industrial Partnership team to design, make and promote their own model F1 car, using 3D printing and 3D models to refine their concept and ideas.

      The exciting STEM (Science, Technology, Engineering and Maths) project took place over 5 days at the start of the new year to help inspire students to explore the world of engineering and to support any potential decisions to study STEM based subjects in the future.

      A team of mentors from the NAC Group delivered the Industrial Cadets Programme and are currently supporting three teams from The Studio to enter the full F1 challenge later in the year. Students are hoping to beat the competition for a place in the finals, which take place in Austin, Texas USA.

      The NAC Group mentors for The Studio – George Cox and Rhys Nimmo, who both got through to the world finals twice whilst representing Wales, have been teaching students the skills needed to be successful whilst working together towards one common goal; including team work, presentation skills and time management.

      Viktoria H from Year 11 took part in the Industrial Cadets programme and said:

      “Industrial Cadets has allowed me to develop my team management skills and is allowing me to further enhance my F1 experience. I have really enjoyed the week and it has been a real eye opener into the engineering world.”

      Sophie W from Year 13 also attended the workshops. She said:

      “Overall I have really enjoyed this experience as it has enabled me to use my graphic design and enterprise skills to create the marketing within the team, helping me to realise were my strengths and weakness are. It has also helped me to think about my future career.”

      George Cox from NAC Group mentored students throughout the programme. He said:

      “This is the second cohort of students from The Studio we’ve had for the week and once again they have amazed Rhys and I with the standard of work for the engineering and portfolio based element of the course. The students have managed to innovate and collaborate with each other to produce some of the best quality work we’ve seen on our course and we are looking forward to continuing our relationship with The Studio!”

      Michael Saint-Cricq, Leader for BTEC and Vocational Education at The Studio attended the workshops with the students. He said:

      “I have thoroughly enjoyed this week working with the students and the passionate and innovative team from the NAC Group. It has been an absolute pleasure watching George and Rhys working with our students and passing on their infectious passion and knowledge for F1. I would highly recommend anyone interested in the STEM subjects to get involved with F1 in Schools with the NAC Group.”
    </content>
  </article>
  <article date="05/09/2018" title="Another test article">
    <title>EXPLORING MUSIC WITH THE MIND</title>
    <headerImage>http://thestudioliverpool.uk/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/FullSizeRender.jpg</headerImage>
    <content>
      Last term students at The Studio attended a presentation hosted by an inspiring composer and musician from Liverpool.

      Mark Rowland has suffered from severe cerebral palsy since birth and lives independently in Sefton Park with his carers. He has pursued his passion for music throughout his life and now works with local school groups to share his talent and knowledge across the city. Mark has performed with Jools Holland and composed a track with DJ Fresh as part of the MindTunes project in partnership with Smirnoff.

      Mark visited The Studio to talk specifically about the technological barriers he faces when trying to live independently. He discussed communication technology, including his Tobi II eye-gaze controlled communication computer and the challenges he faces including accessibility, interfaces and cost. Students were challenged to think about problems Mark may face and how he could overcome them using technology.

      The session offered an incredible insight into Mark’s life and success as a composer and students were inspired by his journey. Mark said:

      “I love to get involved in projects which help to change people’s presumptions about disability. If I can increase their awareness of real-life situations and increase their enjoyment working with people who have barriers then it’s worthwhile. I hope it improves their knowledge and gives them ideas to use to improve their community. I look forward to working with students at The Studio on solutions in the future.”

      Daniel C from Year 13 said:

      “Seeing Mark’s presentation on how disabled people use technology to make their lives easier and achieve their goals in life really motivated me to want to help explore new ways their lives and meeting their goals in life can be made easier. Technology has come so far in supporting disabled to live normal lives whilst breaking down the barrier that surrounds the idea that people with disabilities cannot contribute to society in the same way as others.”

      Since Mark’s visit to The Studio, students and staff have been working together on a project to explore assisted technology further. Lauren Archer, Media Coach at The Studio said:

      “Meeting Mark really inspired me. Despite his challenges in life he has worked hard to do what he loves; create music. Mark was a huge inspiration to the students and I think it was a fantastic opportunity for them to see how technology has enhanced his life. Mark showed his humorous side, was honest and showed his great determination. I really think Mark’s presentation will be the start of great things for the students at The Studio and will encourage them to look at helping people with disabilities use technology and how they can personally make an impact.”

      Listen to the track ‘Mindtunes’ below. All proceeds from the track support Queen Elizabeth’s Foundation for disabled people.
    </content>
  </article>
</news>


<!--
<article date="" title="">
  <title>  </title>
  <headerImage>  </headerImage>
  <content>
  
  </content>
</article>
-->
